five asks how many stereoisomers are
possible for the following compound we
need to understand that this depends on
how many stereo centers there are on the
compound for example if you have one
chyro Center that chyro Center can be r
or it can be S and then if you have two
chyro centers now we have more
possibilities so what the formula is is
2 to the N the number of chyro centers n
you take two and raise it to that power
and that's how many stereo isomers are
possible how many KY Centers do we have
well we have one right here there's that
bromine the implied hydrogen and then
the two directions of the Ring we have
one right here as well because we have
this substituent and then the two
directions of the ring as well as the
implied hydrogen and then this also is a
chyro center because that chlorine can
be on the dash or the wedge and that
will be different because we've got
chlorine hydrogen methyl and then the
rest of the molecule so if we have three
chyal centers then we're saying that's
two